Meet Fievel. In his search to find his family, he discovered America.
An American Tail is a animation, comedy, adventure film directed by Don Bluth.
A young mouse named Fievel and his family decide to migrate to America,
a "land without cats," at the turn of the 20th century.
But somehow, Fievel ends up in the New World alone and must fend off not only the felines he never
thought he'd have to deal with again but also the loneliness of being away from home.
Fievel Mousekewitz (voice), played by Phillip Glasser.
Mama Mousekewitz (voice), played by Erica Yohn.
Papa Mousekewitz (voice), played by Nehemiah Persoff.
Tanya Mousekewitz (voice), played by Amy Green.
Henri (voice), played by Christopher Plummer.
Warren T. Rat (voice), played by John Finnegan.
An American Tail is a 1986 American animated musical comedy-drama film
directed by Don Bluth and written by Judy Freudberg and Tony Geiss.
The film stars the voices of Phillip Glasser, John Finnegan, Amy Green, Nehemiah
Persoff, Dom DeLuise, Madeline Kahn, and Christopher Plummer.
It is the story of Fievel Mousekewitz and his family as they emigrate from the Russian Empire to the
United States for freedom, but Fievel gets lost and must find a way to reunite with them.
The film was released in the United States on
November 21, 1986, by Universal Pictures.
It received mixed reviews from critics, and grossed $84
million against a budget of $9 million.
The film spawned a franchise, including a sequel, An American Tail: Fievel Goes West (1991), a television series, Fievel's American Tails (1992) and two
direct-to-video sequels, An American Tail: The Treasure of Manhattan Island (1998) and An American Tail: The Mystery of the Night Monster (1999).
The film explores themes of new york city, cat,
immigration, mouse, american dream.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.